# Dhruva Krishnamurthy

# Student @ The University of Michigan

415 S 5th Ave Ann Arbor, MI 48104 (832) 524-3634 dhruva.krishna98@gmail.com

#### **BIO**

A Masters student at the University of Michigan, studying Biostatistics. I have 2 years experience in the financial sector, utilising programs and languages such as Python, Tableau and Excel to build automated analytics dashboards. Eagerly looking for opportunities in any sector involving machine learning, data analytics and data visualisation.

# **SKILLS**

Python (Pandas, Keras, Scikit-Learn, Matplotlib), Tableau, Microsoft SQL Server, R, Microsoft Excel, MATLAB

Machine Learning, Data Visualisation, Statistical Modelling

### **EXPERIENCE**

**Independent, Remote** - Freelance Writer

DEC 2020 - PRESENT

Frequently publish articles centered around Data Science, Statistical Analysis, Data Visualisation and interesting real-world applications of these concepts.

Published in a series of Medium publications, including *Towards Data Science*, *Towards AI* and *Data Driven Investor* with over 20,000 individual views.

Founder of a Substack publication called *Algo-Fin*, a newsletter dedicated to discussing algorithmic trading strategies and visualisations for the foreign exchange market with a macroeconomic focus.

#### **Freepoint Commodities, London** - Data Scientist

SEP 2019 - AUG 2020

Responsible for the production and analysis of a series of complex models to understand the power markets in Europe.

Built, maintained and visualised algorithms in supply stack predictions, power generation forecasting and demand regressions for major European countries.

Utilised Python, Tableau, Microsoft SQL Server and Microsoft Excel.

# Workplace Fabric, London - Data Analyst

MAY 2019 - AUG 2019

Produced efficient and scalable machine learning models for a software-based IoT company and conducted a series of data visualisations on IoT data streams.

Workplace Fabric, London - Workshop and Installation Technician

MAY 2016 - AUG 2019 (PART TIME)

Involved in the preparation and installation of IoT devices in office spaces to analyse workspace management.

Responsible for organising installations and ensuring seamless integration of devices into offices.

# **Independent, Remote** - Maths Tutor

JAN 2015 - AUG 2019 (PART TIME)

Over 4 years experience tutoring multiple students in GCSE and A-Level Mathematics. Responsible for producing worksheets, grading papers and generating custom lesson plans for each individual student depending on their specific needs.

# **EDUCATION**

**University of Nottingham** - BSc Data Science

2016 - 2019

**University of Michigan** - MS Biostatistics

2021 - 2023

#### Links

LinkedIn - https://bit.ly/3DjUla0

Medium - https://dhruva-krishna.medium.com

Substack - https://algofin.substack.com